irishgenealogy.ie 2019-07-23

# Privacy Policy - Irish Genealogy

##  [ Cookie and Privacy Policy](https://www.irishgenealogy.ie/en/privacy-policy)

## General Statement

This policy establishes how The Department of Culture, Heritage and the Gaeltacht will use information we gather about you from your visit to our website. The privacy of our customers is of utmost importance to us. We fully respect your right to privacy, and will not collect any personal information about you on this website without your clear permission.

## Collection and/or use of Personal Information

The Department of Culture, Heritage and the Gaeltacht does not collect any personal data about you on this website, apart from information which you volunteer (by e-mailing us or by using our online feedback form). Any personal information which you provide in this way is not made available to any third parties, save as required by law, and is used by this Department only in line with the purpose for which you provided it.

This website does not send directly any personal data to external websites. We only provide links pre-formatted with the details you entered, to facilitate your search with other websites. These search details are sent only when you click on the link(s), like if you were searching directly on the external website. The clicked links, like any web page your browse, may be stored in your browser history. This may not apply to the search element of the site but no user-identifiable data is stored in the process.

The Department of Culture, Heritage and the Gaeltacht will make no attempt to identify individual visitors, or to associate technical details with any individual. It is our policy never to disclose such technical information in respect of individual website visitors to any third party, unless obliged to disclose such information by a rule of law.

## Usage of SiteImprove Analytics

The following cookies may be set in your visitors web browser if you use the Siteimprove Analytics script on your website.

Cookie name: nmstat  
Cookie type: Persistent – expires after 1000 days  
Domain: www.irishgenealogy.ie

This cookie is used to help record the visitor’s use of the website. It is used to collect statistics about site usage such as when the visitor last visited the site. This information is then used to improve the user experience on the website. This Siteimprove Analytics cookie contains a randomly generated ID used to recognise the browser when a visitor reads a page. The cookie contains no personal information and is used only for web analytics.

Cookie name: siteimproveses  
Cookie type: Session cookie  
Domain: .siteimprove.com

This cookie is used purely to track the sequence of pages a visitor looks at during a visit to the site. This information can be used to reduce user journeys, and enable visitors to find relevant information quicker.

Cookie name: szcookiechoice  
Cookie type: Session cookie  
Domain: .siteimprove.com

This cookie is used to determine if the user has accepted or declined cookies. This is only set if you use the Siteimprove Cookie Info Banner solution.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

The ReCaptcha service on the site uses a number of cookies which are subject to update as the service is amended.

The search application on www.irishgenealogy.ie does not use any cookies except a session cookie.

## Collection and Use of Technical Information

We may collect and store general information for statistical purposes. For example, we may count the number of visitors to the different pages of our website to help make them more useful to visitors. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store only the following information about your visit:

  1. the Internet domain (for example, 'xcompany.com' if you use a private Internet access account, or 'yourschool.edu' if you connect from a university's domain) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our website
  2. the type of browser and operating system used to access our site
  3. the date and time you access our site
  4. the pages you visit
  5. if you visited this Department of Culture, Heritage and the Gaeltacht website from a link on another website, the address of that website.

In short the technical information will be used only by the Department of Culture, Heritage and the Gaeltacht and only for statistical and other administrative purposes.

## Contact Details

Queries:

Cultural Institutions Unit  
Department of Culture, Heritage and the Gaeltacht  
Government Offices, New Road  
Killarney, Co. Kerry.

Email: [civilrecordqueries@ahrrga.gov.ie](mailto:civilrecordqueries@ahrrga.gov.ie).
